Are you a moviegoer?
你是一名影迷吗？
If, like me, you’re a fan of film, then there’s no better place to watch something than on the big screen at the cinema.
如果你和我一样热爱电影，那么没有什么地方比电影院的大屏幕更适合观影了。
You enter the dark auditorium and take your seat, ready to be entertained.
你走进昏暗的放映厅，落座之后，便准备好开启一场视听盛宴。
But while you engross yourself in some movie magic, many others are now getting their film fix at home.
但就在你沉浸于电影的奇幻魅力时，如今有许多人选择在家就能过足电影瘾。
Over the last few years, cinemas have seen a resurgence.
在过去几年里，电影院行业迎来了复苏。
Customers have been enticed by comfortable seats, and lots of choice of things to watch.
舒适的座椅以及丰富多样的影片选择，吸引了不少观众前来。
Multiplexes in particular can screen up to twenty films at the same time, catering for all different tastes.
尤其是多厅影院，能够同时放映多达二十部影片，满足不同观众的口味。
In addition, 3D and even 4D movies can give the audience an extra immersive experience.
此外，3D甚至4D电影还能为观众带来更具沉浸感的体验。
So, what’s not to like about a trip to the cinema?
如此说来，去电影院观影还有什么让人不满意的地方呢？
One answer to that question is convenience.
这个问题的答案之一就是便利性。
Rather than going out, it’s so much easier to stay in and watch a romcom or action movie on a high-definition TV screen via a streaming service such as Netflix or Amazon Prime.
比起出门，待在家里通过网飞或亚马逊Prime这类流媒体平台，在高清电视屏幕上看一部浪漫喜剧或动作片要轻松得多。
There’s plenty of choice, and it’s relatively cheap as well.
影片选择十分丰富，价格也相对实惠。
But, personally, I find there are too many distractions, and watching at home is not such an event.
但就我个人而言，我觉得在家观影干扰太多，和影院观影完全不是一回事。
I miss the trailers too!
我还很想念电影预告片呢！
But the coronavirus pandemic has put the future of cinemas under the spotlight.
但新冠疫情的爆发让电影院的未来被推上了风口浪尖。
Some have had to close because of reduced ticket sales.
部分影院因票房收入下滑而不得不关门歇业。
And in the UK, it’s brought about a surge in TV watching and online streaming, according to media watchdog, Ofcom.
英国媒体监管机构英国通信管理局表示，疫情还使得英国的电视观看量和在线流媒体播放量大幅飙升。
It also found that half of UK adults will keep and continue using their new streaming subscriptions.
该机构还发现，有一半的英国成年人会保留并继续使用他们新订阅的流媒体服务。
This isn’t great news for cinemas.
这对电影院来说绝非好消息。
They rely on the release of a big blockbuster to bring the crowds back, but the launch of new films, such as James Bond: No Time To Die, are being delayed.
它们本指望依靠一部重磅大片的上映来吸引观众回流，但《007：无暇赴死》等新片的上映计划却纷纷被推迟。
And Disney has released its $200m blockbuster, Mulan, online instead of in movie theatres.
迪士尼更是将其耗资2亿美元打造的大片《花木兰》选择在线上发行，而非在影院上映。
But John Fithian, from the National Association of Theatre Owners, told Variety magazine: “This idea of waiting out the pandemic to make your movies more profitable doesn’t make sense to me.
不过，美国影院业主协会的约翰·菲西安在接受《综艺》杂志采访时表示：“这种想着熬过疫情再让电影赚更多钱的想法，在我看来毫无道理。
There won’t be as much of an industry left to play your movies in if you do that.”
如果真这么做，到时候这个行业恐怕就剩不下多少能放映你们影片的影院了。”